SFU Archives reference and display materials collection
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
SFU Archives reference and display materials collection
[ca 1870] - 2002
F-247
5.3 m of textual records 3997 photographs 579 contact sheets 429 negatives 213 slides 15 sketches 2 videocassettes: VHS 1 cassette tape
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Archives and Records Management Department
The University Archives acquires, preserves and makes available three categories of materials: (1) the official records of the University, including those created by the Board of Governors, Senate, University committees, faculties, departments and administrative offices; (2) materials documenting the wider University community; and (3) historical research collections that promote the teaching and research activities of the University.
The Archives was established within the University Library in 1968 when librarian Liisa Fagerlund was appointed University Archivist on a half-time basis. She continued in this post until 1975 when she left the University. From 1975 to 1978, the Archives functioned within the Special Collections division of the Library. Archival duties were carried out by various library staff members. In 1978, the University Archives was established as a separate administrative unit outside of the Library. Donald Baird, recently retired as University Librarian, became University Archivist and held this position until his retirement in 1990. Jim Ross served as University Archivist from 1991 to 1993, and was succeeded by Ian Forsyth in 1994.
When the Archives was a function of the University Library, the University Archivist reported to the University Librarian. When the Archives was established as a separate administrative unit, the University Archivist reported directly to the University President. The reporting structure changed in 1986 when the University Archivist reported to the Vice-President, Research/Information Systems; in 1990, when the University Archivist reported to the Associate Vice-President, Academic; and in 1996, when the University Archivist reported to the Registrar/Dean of Students.
published
Full
Published
Title based on the contents of the collection.
Collection predominantly consists of photographic material (photographs, portraits, contact sheets, negatives, proofs, and slides) but also includes textual records such as clippings, publications, news releases, posters, and miscellaneous documents. It mainly comprises publicity material relating to the activities and topics documented by Media and Public Relations and that includes the photographing of SFU people, departments, organizations, places, and campus events for producing press releases, brochures, and other University publications.
Arrangement follows the Media and Public Affairs office's internal filing scheme from which most of the materials originated.
Archives and Records Management Department; University Communications and Marketing; Photographic materials; Sound recordings; Moving images; Textual records
Material was originally collected and donated to the Archives by the Media and Public Relations office.
No further accruals are expected.
Over the years, the University Archives acquired a variety of materials from the Media and Public Relations office (since 2006 known as Public Affairs and Media Relations). These materials were retained for their informational value although they were never formally integrated with the Media and Public Relations fonds (F-61). Archives staff used this material to create displays and to answer reference questions. Over the years, they added additional files originating from other University departments.
Originally, the Media and Public Relations office kept these materials in their internal files so they could keep track of potential story leads. Additional files have been added to the collection since the Media and Public Relations fonds first had been processed. Even though the materials held little evidential value for the Media and Public Relations office, their residual informational value made it worthwhile to combine them with similar material previously collected by the Archives.
See the inventories for Media and Public Relations fonds (F-61) and the Dennis Roberts fonds (F-160). In 1966, the University hired Roberts, an experienced newsman and public relations director, as its first full-time information officer. Roberts wrote news releases and prepared brochures, some of which is included in the SFU Archives Reference and Display Materials collection.
Most files in the collection have an open access status, but some of the files may contain personal or confidential information. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release and, as a result of the review, access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
File list is available for all series.
- Portraits, [ca 1960] - 2002; F-247-1; 1.55 m of textual records 1254 photographs 412 contact sheets 137 negatives 56 slides
  published
  Series consists of photographic material of faculty, administrative officers, chancellors, presidents, board of governors, honorary degree recipients, as well as biographical notes, curricula vitæ, news clippings, and published articles.
  All files are open unless indicated otherwise at the sub-series levels.
  - Communication, [196-] - 1986; F-247-1-1; 2 cm of textual records 17 photographs 6 contact sheets
    Sub-series consists of photos, contact sheets, negatives, proofs, articles, and published material relating to individuals from the School of Communication. For a list of faculty members associated with the sub-series, see access points.
    Bawtree, Michael; George, Donald A.; Lyndon, P.; Mallinson, Thomas J.; Gail Martin; R. Murray Schafer; Smith, Joel; Smythe, Dallas; School of Communication; Richards, Bill
    The records are open with no restrictions.
    - Bawtree, Michael; also Education, 1966; F-247-1-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Textual records
      Open
      Creator's original file classification code: Helcermanas.
    - George, Donald A., 1983; F-247-1-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: UNS 83.1.11 [5].
    - Lyndon, Patrick, [ca 1960] - [ca 1970]; F-247-1-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - Mallinson, Tom J., 1966 - 1984; F-247-1-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: Helcermanas, IMC 70009 [9], UNS.
    - Martin, Gail, 1980 - 1986; F-247-1-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: Article, obituary: SFU Week: Vol. 18, No. 10.
    - Richards, Bill, [ca 1980]; F-247-1-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - Schafer, R. Murray, 1966; F-247-1-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - Smith, Joel, [ca 1975]; F-247-1-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: Haney Correctional Inst..
    - Smythe, Dallas; Professor Emeriti, [ca 1979] - [ca 1980]; F-247-1-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: IMC11-170, Peak 79189.
  - Computing Science, 1987 - 1996; F-247-1-2; 2 photographs
    Sub-series consists of photos, contact sheets, negatives, proofs, articles, and published material relating to individuals from the School of Computing Science. For a list of faculty members associated with the sub-series, see access points.
    Sterling, Ted; Benston, Maggie
    - Sterling, T., 1987; F-247-1-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: UNS 87310-04.
    - Benston, Maggie; Chemistry (later Women's Studies), 1995 - 1996; F-247-1-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: Archives, M&PR.
  - Kinesiology, 1969 - 1991; F-247-1-3; 1 cm of textual records 15 photographs
    Sub-series consists of photos, articles, and published material relating to individuals from the Department of Biomedical Physiology and Kinesiology. For a list of faculty members associated with this sub-series, see access points.
    Banister, Eric W.; Duncan, Ray; Ross, William; David Stirling; John George Wilkinson; Kinesiology Faculty; Department of Biomedical Physiology and Kinesiology
    - Banister, Eric; Duncan, Ray; Ross, William, [ca 1969]; F-247-1-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - Stirling, David, [ca 1981] - 1985; F-247-1-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: M SF Week: April 2, 1981.
    - Wilkinson, John George, 1984; F-247-1-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: SFU Week; June 14, 1984.
    - Kinesiology Faculty, [ca 1991]; F-247-1-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: Ron Long, LIDC.
  - Engineering, 1984 - 1986; F-247-1-4; 10 photographs
    Sub-series consists of photos, articles, and published material relating to individuals from the School of Engineering Science. For a list of faculty members associated with this sub-series, see access points.
    McGeer, B.T.; School of Engineering Science
    - McGeer, B.T. (Tad), 1984 - 1986; F-247-1-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: SF Week: June 20, 1985.
  - Anthropology, 1987; F-247-1-5; 1 photograph
    Sub-series consists of photos relating to individuals from the Department of Sociology and Anthropology. For individuals associated with the sub-series, see access points.
    Dickie-Clarke, H.; Department of Sociology and Anthropology
    - Dickie-Clarke, H.; Professor Emeriti, [ca 1987]; F-247-1-5-0-1 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: UNS 87315-10.
  - Archaeology, [ca 1970] - [199-]; F-247-1-6; 1 cm of textual records 19 photos
    Sub-series consists of photos, articles, and published material relating to individuals from the Department of Archaeology. For a list of faculty members associated with the sub-series, see access points.
    Carlson, Roy L.; Percy, Rick; Shutler, Richard, Jr.; Stephens, Editha; Department of Archaeology
    - Carlson, R.L., [197-]; F-247-1-6-0-1 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - Percy, Rick, 1982 - 1990; F-247-1-6-0-2 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: SF Week stories, M&PR.
    - Shutler, R.; Professor Emeriti, [ca 1986]; F-247-1-6-0-3 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: UNS 86326-13.
    - Stephens, Dr. Editha; Visiting Professor, 1975 - 1981; F-247-1-6-0-4 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: M&PR: Comment.
  - Criminology, 1980 - 1986; F-247-1-7; 1 photograph
    Sub-series consists of photos, articles, and published material relating to individuals from the School of Criminology. For a list of faculty members associated with the sub-series, see access points.
    Chappell, Duncan; School of Criminology
    - Chappel, Duncan; Criminology, 1980 - 1986; F-247-1-7-0-1 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: The Newsmakers, M&PR.
  - Economics and Commerce, [ca 1966] - [ca 1983]; F-247-1-8; 1 cm of textual records 7 photographs 1 contact sheet 1 negative
    Sub-series consists of photos, articles, and published material relating to individuals from the Department of Economics. For a list of faculty members associated with the sub-series, see access points.
    Copes, Parzival; Dixon, William; Matthews, John; McCallum, John; Okuda, Kenji; Department of Economics
    - Copes, Parzival, 1966 - [ca 1983]; F-247-1-8-0-1 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - Dixon, William, [ca 1973]; F-247-1-8-0-2 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: LIDC 73025 [3].
    - Matthews, John; Dean of Arts, [ca 1968] - [ca 1969]; F-247-1-8-0-3 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - McCallum, John, 1982; F-247-1-8-0-4 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: SF Week: Vol. 26, No. 11.
    - Okuda, Kenji, 1969; F-247-1-8-0-5 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: IMC 69068-6.
  - English, [ca 1960] - 1997; F-247-1-9; 4 cm of textual records 40 photographs 59 contact sheets 5 negatives
    Sub-series consists of photos, articles, and published material relating to individuals from the Department of English. For a list of faculty members associated with the sub-series, see access points.
    Baker, Ron; Campbell, D.A.; Candelaria, Frederick; Conibear, Ken; Cook, Clark; Cooperman, Stanley; Dunham, Robert; Elliott, G.R.; Elwood, H.C.W.; Frazer, Frances M.; Maud, Ralph; Molyneux, G.T.; Sellers, W.H.; Stephens, Raymond; Sullivan, Dale; Web, Eugene; Zaslove, Jerald; Department of English; Mills, John; Blaser, Robin
    - Baker, Ron J., [ca 1960] - [ca 1975]; F-247-1-9-0-1 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: Jennings Photographer.
    - Blaser, R., 1979; F-247-1-9-0-2 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: Peak 79040-13.
    - Campbell, D.A., 1965; F-247-1-9-0-3 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: Helcermanas; Pacific.
    - Candelaria, Frederick, 1965; F-247-1-9-0-4 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - Conibear, Ken, 1997; F-247-1-9-0-5 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: SF Week: Sept 18, 1997.
    - Cook, Clark, 1965; F-247-1-9-0-6 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - Cooperman, Stanley, 1965; F-247-1-9-0-7 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: Helcermanas Photographer.
    - Dunham, Dr. Robert H., 1986 - 1990; F-247-1-9-0-8 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: M&PR, SFU Week.
    - Elliott, G.R., 1965; F-247-1-9-0-9 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - Elwood, H.C.W., 1965; F-247-1-9-0-10 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - Frazer, Frances M., 1965; F-247-1-9-0-11 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - Maud, Ralph N., 1965; F-247-1-9-0-12 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - Mills, John, 1965; F-247-1-9-0-13 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - Molyneux, G.T., 1965; F-247-1-9-0-14 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - Sellers, W.H., 1965; F-247-1-9-0-15 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - Stephens, Raymond, 1965; F-247-1-9-0-16 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - Sullivan, Dale H., 1965 - [ca 1970]; F-247-1-9-0-17 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: Helcermanas; IMC 27-2-70.
    - Web, Eugene, 1965; F-247-1-9-0-18 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - Zaslove, Jerald, 1965; F-247-1-9-0-19 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - English Professors, [ca 1966]; F-247-1-9-0-20 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
  - Geography, 1965 - 2000; F-247-1-10; 1 cm of textual records 16 photos 3 contact sheets 1 negative
    Sub-series consists of photos relating to individuals from the Department of Geography. For a list of faculty members associated with the sub-series, see access points.
    Brown, Robert C.; Cunningham, Frank; Eliot-Hurst, M.E.; MacPherson, Archibald; Pierce, John T.; Wagner, P.; Wilson, James W.; Department of Geography
    - Brown, Robert C., [ca 1970] - [ca 1979]; F-247-1-10-0-1 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: Peak.
    - Cunningham, Frank, 1966 - 1978; F-247-1-10-0-2 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: Helcermanas, UNS 78220.
    - Eliot-Hurst, M.E., [ca 1970] - [ca 1979]; F-247-1-10-0-3 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
    - MacPherson, Archibald, 1965 - [ca 1969]; F-247-1-10-0-4 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: Williams Bros. Photographer.
    - Pierce, John; Dean of Arts, [ca 2000]; F-247-1-10-0-5 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: LIDC.
    - Wagner, P.; Professor Emeriti, 1972; F-247-1-10-0-6 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: LIDC 72015-1.
    - Wilson, J.; Professor Emeriti, 1983; F-247-1-10-0-7 (Archival box - standard 247-1)
      Creator's original file classification code: UND 83225-7.
  - History, 1966 - 1997; F-247-1-11; 5 cm of textual records 29 photographs 29 contact sheets 6 negatives
    Sub-series consists of photos, articles, and published material relating to individuals from the Department of History. For a list of faculty members associated with the sub-series, see access points.
    Aberbach, A.D.; Auty, Phyllis; Bumsted, J.M.; Cole, Doug; Cook, George; Cunningham, Allan B.; Evans, Lawrence; Hamilton, Charles L.; Stigger, Philip; Strong-Boag, Veronica; Sullivan, Richard; Tippett, Maria; Williams, Warren E.; Department of History
    - Aberbach, A.D., 1966; F-247-1-11-0-1 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Auty, Phyllis, 1966; F-247-1-11-0-2 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Bumsted, J.M., 1966; F-247-1-11-0-3 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Cole, Douglas, 1997; F-247-1-11-0-4 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
      Creator's original file classification code: Faculty Association Newsletter obituary, Sept. 16, 1997.
    - Cook, George, [ca 1969]; F-247-1-11-0-5 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Cunningham, Allen B., 1966 - [ca 1979]; F-247-1-11-0-6 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Evans, Lawrence, 1966; F-247-1-11-0-7 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Hamilton, Charles; Academic Planner, [ca 1980]; F-247-1-11-0-8 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Koepke, Robert L., 1966; F-247-1-11-0-9 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Stigger, Philip, 1966; F-247-1-11-0-10 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Strong-Boag, Veronica, 1983 - 1991; F-247-1-11-0-11 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
      Creator's original file classification code: M SF Week.
    - Sullivan, Richard, 1980 - 1986; F-247-1-11-0-12 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
      Creator's original file classification code: M SF Week Vol. 18 No. 4.
    - Tippett, Maria, 1982; F-247-1-11-0-13 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
      Creator's original file classification code: SFU Week; June 24, 1982.
    - Williams, Warren E., 1966; F-247-1-11-0-14 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - History professors - negatives (copies), 1966; F-247-1-11-0-15 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
  - Modern Languages, 1966 - 1986; F-247-1-12; 6 cm of textual records 36 photographs 55 contact sheets 6 negatives
    Sub-series consists of photos, articles, and published material relating to individuals from the Department of Linguistics. For a list of faculty members associated with the sub-series, see access points.
    Altmann, Annaliese; Bird, Genevieve C.; Bursill-Hall, Geoffrey L.; Clark, B.K.; Colard, Marie-Helene; Davis, P.W.; Dearmond, R.C.; Delord, J.; Foley, James; Garcia, Dr. Jorge; Hammerly, Hector; Holliday, G.F.; Kaneen, Brian O.; Kim, T.W.; Newton, Brian E.; Shoolbraid, G.M.H.; Saunders, Ross; Tarpent, Marie-Lucie; Whieldon, G.G.; Department of Linguistics
    - Altmann, Annaliese, 1966; F-247-1-12-0-1 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Bird, Genivieve C., 1966; F-247-1-12-0-2 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Bursill-Hall, G.L., 1966 - 1985; F-247-1-12-0-3 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Clark, B.K.; Teaching Assistant, 1966; F-247-1-12-0-4 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
      Creator's original file classification code: Pacific Photographic Services Ltd..
    - Colard, Marie-Helene, 1966; F-247-1-12-0-5 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Davis, P.W., 1966; F-247-1-12-0-6 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Dearmond, R.C., 1966; F-247-1-12-0-7 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Delord, J., 1966; F-247-1-12-0-8 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Foley, James, 1966; F-247-1-12-0-9 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Garcia, Jorge, 1966; F-247-1-12-0-10 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Hammerly, Hector, 1966; F-247-1-12-0-11 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Holliday, G.F., 1966; F-247-1-12-0-12 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Kaneen, Brian O., 1966; F-247-1-12-0-13 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Kim, T.W., 1966; F-247-1-12-0-14 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Newton, Brian E., 1966 - 1974; F-247-1-12-0-15 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
      Creator's original file classification code: Helcermanas, Comment.
    - Shoolbraid, G.M.H., 1966; F-247-1-12-0-16 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Saunders, Ross, 1986; F-247-1-12-0-17 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
      Creator's original file classification code: LIDC 86137-2.
    - Tarpent, Marie-Lucie, 1966; F-247-1-12-0-18 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Whieldon, G.G., 1966; F-247-1-12-0-19 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - [Unidentified proofs], 1966; F-247-1-12-0-20 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
  - Philosophy, 1966; F-247-1-13; 2 photographs
    Sub-series consists of photos relating to individuals from the Department of Philosophy. For a list of faculty members associated with the sub-series, see access points.
    Grants, Arvid; Department of Philosophy
    - Grants, A.J.; Chair, [ca 1966]; F-247-1-13-0-1 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
      Creator's original file classification code: Williams Bros..
  - Political Science and Anthropology, 1969 - 1979; F-247-1-14; 3 cm of textual records 14 photographs 3 negatives
    Sub-series consists of photos, articles, and published material relating to individuals from the Department of Political Science. For a list of faculty members associated with the sub-series, see access points.
    Adams, Heibert; Bettison, D. G.; Bottomore, Tom B.; Brose, Thomas H.; Halperin, Maurice; Quo, F.; Rush, Gary; Somjee, A.H.; Wyllie, Robert W.; Department of Political Science
    - Adams, Heibert, [ca 1970] - [ca 1979]; F-247-1-14-0-1 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Bettison, D.G., [ca 1970] - [ca 1979]; F-247-1-14-0-2 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Bottomore, Thomas B.; Dean of Arts, [ca 1970] - [ca 1979]; F-247-1-14-0-3 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Brose, Tom, [ca 1970] - [ca 1979]; F-247-1-14-0-4 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Halperin, Maurice, [ca 1970] - [ca 1979]; F-247-1-14-0-5 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
      Creator's original file classification code: UNS, Peak.
    - Quo, F., [ca 1970] - [ca 1979]; F-247-1-14-0-6 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Rush, G.B., 1969; F-247-1-14-0-7 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
      Creator's original file classification code: AVC 17-10-69.
    - Somjee, A.H., [ca 1970] - [ca 1979]; F-247-1-14-0-8 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
    - Wyllie, R.W., [ca 1970] - [ca 1979]; F-247-1-14-0-9 (Archival box - standard 247-2)
  - Psychology, 1966 - 1976; F-247-1-15; 2 cm of textual records 14 photographs 19 contact sheets 1 negative
    Sub-series consists of photos, articles, and published material relating to individuals from the Department of Psychology. For a list of faculty members associated with the sub-series, see access points.
    Ames, Elinor; Cox, F.N.; ingling, Jane; Kendall, Lorne M.; Koopman, Ray; Lyman, Bernard E.; Smith, W. A. S.; Wilson, Lolita; Department of Psychology
    - Ames, Elinor W., 1966; F-247-1-15-0-1 (Archival box - standard 247-3)
      Creator's original file classification code: Helcermanas?.
    - Cox, F.N., 1966; F-247-1-15-0-2 (Archival box - standard 247-3)